https://staffordshirescouts.org.uk/about-us/privacy-policy/

Toggle search form
Toggle navigation
Staffordshire County Scouts
HomeNewsDistricts Burton upon Trent DistrictCannock Chase DistrictLichfield DistrictMoorlands DistrictNewcastle DistrictPotteries North DistrictStafford DistrictStone DistrictTamworth DistrictThree Towns DistrictUttoxeter DistrictKibblestone DistrictSections Beaver ScoutsCub ScoutsScoutsExplorer Scouts Young LeadersScout Network Scouts of the World AwardScout Active SupportTop Awards Queen’s Scout AwardDuke of Edinburgh’s AwardExpeditionsActivities Air ActivitiesCavingClimbing and Abseiling Climbing PermitsClimbing VenuesClimbing CoursesHill Walking Hill Walking Terrain & PermitsHill Walking CoursesMountain BikingWater Activities Water Activities CoursesPermit FundingCounty Adult Activity Weekend County Adult Activity Weekend DetailsTraining Adult Training Course DatesGet InvolvedBadges at Home BeaversCubsScoutsExplorersNetworkInternational African Adventure 2020Kent Jamboree 2021Kandersteg Winter Adventure 2022Denmark Jamboree 2022Contact Details
Return to Staffordshire Scouts
Privacy Policy
Privacy statement
Staffordshire County Scouts and The Scout Association take the issue of privacy very seriously and we are committed to protecting and respecting our users’ privacy. This Privacy Statement sets out our current data processing practices and should be read in conjunction with our terms and conditions. If you have any queries or concerns regarding these practices, you should contact the County Office at admin@staffordshirescouts.org.uk
1. The information we collect
The only circumstances in which we will provide any of your personal data to a third party for non commercial purposes are those contained in this Privacy Policy.
2. Registration information
When you register with Staffordshire County Scouts, we ask for your name, email address and postcode. We usually also capture your IP address at the time you register.
3. Sharing of data
We may share data supplied by you (or collected about you) with other parts of The Scout Association eg Scout Shops Ltd.
4. Advertising
Staffordshire County Scouts may include interactive advertising for other businesses as part of the site operation. We may use, and provide to third parties, your contact details if you have given us permission to do so.
5. Legal jurisdiction
All personal information and details held on and processed by computers situated in the United Kingdom.
6. Further information
Staffordshire County Scouts will as part of it’s normal operation send out to information emails. Members can decide to ask for these emails as they register.
7. Disclosure of data by order of a Court and Security
We reserve the right to communicate a Member’s personal information as we hold to third parties who are empowered by regulation, statute or order of a court.
We have security measures in place to protect our customer database. Access to this database is restricted internally.
However, it remains each Member’s responsibility:
to keep their password secret
to protect against unauthorised access to your personal details
to log off from the staffordshirescouts.org.uk service when not using it; and
to ensure against use by anyone else of the staffordshirescouts.org.uk Service through the machine that Member uses while they are “logged on” to the staffordshirescouts.org.uk service
to search and obtain only the data specifically required and allowed for relating to their role.
8. Use of cookies by The Scout Association
Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer by websites that you visit. They are widely used in order to make websites work, or work more efficiently, as well as to provide information to the owners of the site
The table below explains the cookies we use and why.
Cookie
Name
Purpose
More information
Google Analytics
_utma_utmb_utmc_utmz
These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited.
Click here for an overview of privacy at Google
Session cookies
res_widthres_heightPHPSESSID
These cookies are used to optimise you screen resolution for user logged in areas. These are session cookies and only last as long as you browser is open
These cookies are essential to the running of the site and member areas.
Style cookie
style
This cookies determines you default font size for staffordshirescouting.org. On the main menu of staffordshirescouting.org you can increase or decrease you font size.
We are working towards developing a new system that will remove the need for this Cookie.
Most web browsers allow some control of most cookies through the browser settings. To find out more about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set and how to manage and delete them, visit www.allaboutcookies.org.
To opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites visit http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout.
YouTube cookies
We embed videos from our official YouTube channel using YouTube’s privacy-enhanced mode. This mode may set cookies on your computer once you click on the YouTube video player, but YouTube will not store personally-identifiable cookie information for playbacks of embedded videos using the privacy-enhanced mode. To find out more please visit YouTube’s embedding videos information page.
9. The Data Protection act
You can obtain further information about data protection laws by visiting the Information Commissioner’s website at http://www.ico.org.uk/for_organisations/data_protection
10. Contacting Staffordshire County Scouts
If you want to contact us to raise any questions about this privacy statement, or any general matters relating to staffordshirescouts.org.uk, you can contact us using this email address: admin@staffordshirescouts.org.uk.
Please use this address if you wish to request from us a copy of the personal data we hold about you. Please note that under English law we are entitled to charge you a fee for providing this service.
11. Google Analytics
Visitors to this website who have javascript enabled are tracked using Google Analytics. Google Analytics collects the following types of information from users:
Type of user agent (web browser) used, software manufacture and version number.
Type of operating system
Screen colors (color processing ability of the users screen)
Javascript support
Flash version
Screen resolution
Network location and IP address
Can include country, city, state, region, county, or any other geographic data.
Hostname
Bandwidth (internet connection speed)
Time of visit
Pages visited
Time spent on each page of the website
Referring site statistics
The website (URI) the user came through in order to arrive at this website (example: clicking on a hyperlink from Yahoo.com that took the user to this website)
Search engine query used (example: typing in a phrase into a search engine like Google, and clicking on a link from that search engine)
This data is only used to optimize our website for our visitors.
This data DOES NOT include any personalized identification information such as:
Names
Phone numbers
Email addresses
Mailing addresses
Bank account numbers
Credit card information
Want to Join? Do you want to become a Scout? Click here to find your nearest Group.
Alternitively, look at our Districts pages to find the Group best suited for you.
CEOP
Admin
Log in
Entries feed
Comments feed
WordPress.org
In this section
Staffordshire Scouts
Safeguarding
Safety
Privacy Policy
General Links
Archives Archives
Select Month
November 2020  (1)
May 2020  (1)
April 2020  (2)
March 2020  (3)
February 2020  (3)
January 2020  (1)
December 2019  (1)
November 2019  (5)
October 2019  (1)
September 2019  (2)
May 2019  (1)
February 2019  (2)
January 2019  (5)
December 2018  (1)
November 2018  (1)
October 2018  (2)
September 2018  (1)
August 2018  (1)
February 2018  (1)
January 2018  (1)
December 2017  (4)
November 2017  (2)
October 2017  (2)
September 2017  (1)
July 2017  (3)
June 2017  (1)
April 2017  (3)
March 2017  (2)
February 2017  (1)
January 2017  (2)
December 2016  (6)
November 2016  (6)
October 2016  (1)
September 2016  (3)
August 2016  (2)
July 2016  (2)
June 2016  (1)
May 2016  (1)
April 2016  (2)
March 2016  (1)
February 2016  (5)
January 2016  (4)
December 2015  (2)
November 2015  (1)
October 2015  (1)
September 2015  (6)
August 2015  (3)
July 2015  (3)
June 2015  (1)
May 2015  (2)
April 2015  (2)
March 2015  (1)
February 2015  (1)
January 2015  (2)
December 2014  (2)
November 2014  (4)
October 2014  (4)
September 2014  (5)
August 2014  (4)
July 2014  (1)
June 2014  (3)
May 2014  (3)
April 2014  (4)
March 2014  (2)
January 2014  (5)
November 2013  (1)
October 2013  (4)
September 2013  (1)
August 2013  (1)
© 2012 - 2020 Staffordshire County Scouts
Charity number: 1021182
No sections of this website may be copied or reproduced without written permission.
Made with
by Graphene Themes.
This website uses cookies to improve your experience. We'll assume you're ok with this, but you can opt-out if you wish - click the read more link for details how to do this.Accept Reject Read MorePrivacy & Cookies Policy
Close
Privacy Overview
This website uses cookies to improve your experience while you navigate through the website. Out of these, the cookies that are categorized as necessary are stored on your browser as they are essential for the working of basic functionalities of the website. We also use third-party cookies that help us analyze and understand how you use this website. These cookies will be stored in your browser only with your consent. You also have the option to opt-out of these cookies. But opting out of some of these cookies may affect your browsing experience.
Necessary
Always Enabled
Necessary cookies are absolutely essential for the website to function properly. This category only includes cookies that ensures basic functionalities and security features of the website. These cookies do not store any personal information.
Non-necessary
Non-necessary
Any cookies that may not be particularly necessary for the website to function and is used specifically to collect user personal data via analytics, ads, other embedded contents are termed as non-necessary cookies. It is mandatory to procure user consent prior to running these cookies on your website.
